today i want to show you a comment that
i think everyone that uses mac os
developer or non-developer should be
aware of that command is called
caffeinate with caffeinate you can stop
your macos from going to sleep this is
very useful for when you are in
situations like for example downloading
or uploading a very heavy file or
reading a book in your computer or
looking at a spreadsheet or running a
command line application and you don't
want your computer to go to sleep and
also you don't want to have to be always
moving your mouse to keep the computer
awake the caffeinated command comes
pre-installed in every mac os so you
don't have to download anything to use
it to use cabinet just open the terminal
whatever you use the terminal
application or itune if you are a
developer and just write the word
caffeinate and press enter and that's it
for as long as caffenet is running and
for as long as your computer has battery
your computer is not going to sleep now
if you want to stop caffeine from
running all you have to do is go back to
the terminal and press ctrl c that will
kill the process and that will allow
your computer to go to sleep normally
confident also has some extra functions
that you might find useful using the t
argument you're going to specify for how
long you want to run caffeinate in
seconds you can specify a timeout a time
when caffeinate will automatically stop
so if you are downloading something
that's going to take maybe 30 minutes to
finish but you want to go to sleep right
now because you're tired you cannot wait
then what you do is you run caffeinate
followed by dash t and then 30 minutes
in two seconds which is going to be 1800
and that's it catherine will keep the
computer awake for 30 minutes and after
that time has passed then caffenet will
exit will kill the process and your
computer will go to sleep normally there
are also other commands like dash m that
stops your disk from falling asleep and
dash d that keeps your display always on
but most of the time for me running
caffeinate is more than enough just make
sure you have enough power in your
battery when you call caffenet because
caffeinate is going to absolutely
consume all of it until your computer
has no power left and that's it for this
video let me know in the comments if you
knew about caffeinated and if you didn't
let me know what did you use to do to
keep your computer awake were you just
moving them out over and over and over
again i did that a lot so thank you for
watching stay healthy stay free
come to me hey yo see you on the next
one